This is the time known as the Great Pirate Era.
A countless array of pirates go to battle across the seas in search of the One Piece,
the legendary treasure left behind by Gold Roger, King of the Pirates.
Monkey D. Luffy, a boy whose body turned to rubber after eating the gum gum fruit,
set sail to become the next King of the Pirates.
As Luffy and his crew conquer numerous obstacles,
they capture the unwanted attention of the world government,
which will use any means necessary to stop them.
Now this is exciting!
I can't wait to see what kind of adventure's up next!
With a charted course awash in danger and intrigue,
the crew will cut a path across the Grand Line to the New World.
Separated from his crew, Luffy has broken out of Impel Down,
and now with his newfound cohorts is headed to Navy HQ to rescue his brother Ace,
who's scheduled for execution.
A special retrospective before Marineford,
the vow of the Brotherhood.
That Vibra card!
It's Ace's, right?
Uh-huh.
Ace spoke of you often.
I don't know.
It's Ace's, right?
Uh-huh.
Ace spoke of you often.
It's Ace's, right?
That Vibra card!
Uh-huh.
Ace spoke of you often.
I gather the two of you were quite close.
He said you were inseparable in your youth and that you went on many fine adventures together.
Sure did.
We used to race each other all the time, too.
Hey!
You jerk!
You're not gonna beat me this time!
Just wait!
He said you ate together, took naps together, even honed your skills together.
He said you were inseparable in your youth and that you went on many fine adventures together.
Sure did. We used to race each other all the time, too.
Hey! You jerk! You're not gonna beat me this time! Just wait!
He said you ate together, took naps together, even honed your skills together.
Take this!
You're still a long way from kicking my butt.
Those were the best of times.
Well, that's the way your brother used to put it, at least.
I always tried to beat the guy, but I never could quite pull it off.
You know, he hadn't even eaten the devil fruit then, but I still wasn't a match for him.
And then he took off to sea.
Three years before you, I hear. Did you ever see him after that?
I did. It was way back when I was in Alabasta.
Well, I guess giving you a chance to escape was pointless.
Hey!
Hiya, Ace!
It's been a while, hasn't it?
You could say that.
It was just to let you know that I'd be in Alabasta for a few days.
I'm in these waters on some business.
Business, huh?
Yeah. I'm with the Whitebeard Pirates. Catch.
The Whitebeard Pirates?
See this tattoo? That's our mark. And it's my pride.
Huh.
So, Luffy, why don't you and your friends come join us?
Come on, it'll be fun. What do you say?
No thanks.
I had a feeling you'd say that.
That's too bad, because you see, Whitebeard's the greatest pirate I've ever met.
That's why I'm going to help him become King of the Pirates.
And not you, Luffy. Sorry.
That's fine. I guess we'll just have to fight then.
Cheers!
Wait, who said I was joining your crew?
Ace, you sure you don't want to join us?
It'll be fun!
I can't right now. I'm chasing someone.
He's a pirate named Blackbeard.
You see, Blackbeard used to be a member of the Second Division of the Whitebeard Pirates.
He was one of my own men, but he committed the most unforgivable sin a pirate could.
He killed one of his fellow crew members, and then he jumped ship.
As commander of his division, it's my responsibility to take care of him.
There's a little something I wanted you to have.
Here.
Do yourself a favor, and hang on to that.
But it's just to scrap the paper.
That paper will reunite us someday. I'd tuck it away somewhere, for safekeeping.
You don't want it?
No, I do!
It's perfectly natural for a guy to worry...
about his bungling kid brother.
He might be a bit much for all of you to handle.
But take good care of him for me.
Wait, you're leaving already?
Luffy, when next we meet, we'll both be top pirates.
And after that, I met him, Blackbeard, that is, when I was in Mocktown.
Hey, Vetsu!
What's wrong?
Just take my teeth for the horrible!
I'm gonna beat the living crap out of you!
Do you two even have the slightest idea what you're fighting about?
Heh.
So then, are you a pirate?
Yeah, that's right.
How big's your bounty?
30 million.
Uh, 30 million?
For you?
I wouldn't believe it even if I collected it!
Are you calling me a liar, you fat, hairy ape?
Enough!
No way!
The kid just challenged Bellamy.
Luffy slaughtered!
Luffy, hold on!
Mister, we're trying to get to the Sky Island.
Do you know anything about that?
Did she say what I think she said?
Sky Island, what an idiot!
You got me there, kid!
I can't believe you guys are putting open to such a ridiculous legend like an island in the sky!
Especially considering how little you know!
Thing is, the time of pirates' dreams are over!
So when I see people chasing dreams of One Piece, I get disgusted!
Luffy!
Zoro!
No matter what happens, don't fight back!
The Sky Island does exist!
Got something you want to say?
This new era they keep rambling on and on about is a load of crap!
The era when pirates' dream of treasure will come to an end?
Yeah, right!
The dreams of pirates will never end!
Am I right?
It's crazy, but back then I didn't know he was the guy Ace was looking for or what he'd end up doing to him.
What?!
The warlords are teaming up with the marines?!
And they're gonna have a war with Whitebeard and his crew?!
When?!
How?!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, hold on a second!
This, this is way too much for me to take in all at once!
What a foolish man you are. You don't know anything, do you? Now listen, that was only conjecture at this point. I don't have any proof, but I'd say that battle is a high probability.
The world government has laid out their bait, but Captain Whitebeard would never ever allow his maids to be killed.
But even with that knowledge, they have announced the public execution of Port Custee Ace, a powerful and high-ranking commander in his crew.
What's wrong?
They're gonna...execute...
According to this, a pirate named Blackbeard defeated Ace and gave him up to the world government. In return, they invited him to be a warlord.
Ace is my brother! Port Custee Ace, the Fire Fist! You're talking about my brother!
Huh? What?!
I have to go rescue Ace, no matter what it takes!
I could hardly believe it when I heard the news about Ace myself. I see.
So in Mocktown, you met Teach without ever knowing that he was your brother's enemy, huh?
Then it wasn't until Impel Down that you learned the truth.
Blackbeard. I see.
Huh?
So you're... Blackbeard!
Huh? Oh, right. I guess I never gave you my name, did I?
Z-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha! Long time no see, Straw Hat Gloofy!
Hey, I know I am for you. I was surprised myself when I heard you were my old commander's baby brother.
What are you doing down here? You're gonna miss the big show! Don't you wanna be there for your brother's public execution?
Z-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
And this washed-up former Warlord over here.
Yeah, I mean you, Crocodile. I heard you got your ass handed to you, but I didn't know Straw Hat Luffy was the one to do it.
Funny thing is, I was trying to take Crocodile's place as a warlord at the time,
so killing you was about the best way I could think of to show the government I was worthy of the position.
And yet here you are. Fate decided to save you instead.
Better make sure you pay your humble respects at his grave, Straw Hat.
He went and took your place for you, because if it weren't for your brother,
you'd be dead and he'd be walking free.
I knew the pirate that Blackbeard killed.
He was the commander of the 4th Division of the Whitebeard Pirates.
Went by the name of Thatch. He was a loyal friend and good-hearted.
Captain Whitebeard and I go back a long ways, and I owe the old salt a great debt,
so I would often visit his ship back then.
But I didn't notice what Teach was up to until it was too late.
And it was then that Ace sailed out alone after Blackbeard.
As the commander of the 2nd Division of the Whitebeard Pirates,
it was his job to punish Teach for his crime.
Attention all soldiers!
Report to the Gulf!
Prepare for the public execution of Fort Gasteen Ace!
I repeat!
Attention all soldiers!
Report to the Gulf!
We'd better cut them off before they leave, or before the Navy gets to them first!
Hey, hold on a second there, Teach.
We need to talk.
Huh?
What do you know?
It's Commander Ace!
You have no right to call me that anymore.
Use that title with respect, but don't use it at all.
I won't have you mock me.
Fine, have it your way.
But there's one question I'd like to ask first.
Instead of fighting, why don't you become a member of my crew?
I have the perfect plan to rise to the top.
If you stick with me, I swear we can rule the world.
Whitebeard's days are numbered and you know it.
I'm going to be King of the Pirates.
First, I'm headed off to Water 7 to kill Straw Hat Luffy as a special gift to the world government.
Wouldn't hurt to have you along for the fun.
Luffy, huh?
You're out of your mind.
Oh, you know him?
Of course I know him, you sack of crap.
I'm not going to let you kill my little brother.
Ugh.
And I'm not joining your crew.
You can take your little offer and shove it up your...
Well, you get it.
Key.
Fly your fears!
Ah!
All right, Ace.
You want to finish me, don't you?
The murder of a fellow crewmate is a serious crime, after all.
And yes, I killed 4th Division Commander Thatcher with my own hands.
You know the rules. On White Beard's ship, whoever finds one of those gets to eat it.
I memorized the shapes and colors of all the devil fruits that they discovered,
so I knew that was the one I needed.
Then you murdered him in cold blood and stole it, without a second thought.
Bad luck for him.
There's no other way. This ability has chosen me.
And its powers may be the strongest man in the world.
Watch. Even among the Logia Fruits, there's nothing quite like it.
Ace, your body is made of fire, right?
My body is dark dance!
Firefly.
Firey doll!
Oh!
I wonder what's going on here.
If you're a Logia type, that shouldn't hurt you.
Or rather, it shouldn't even hit you.
Oh!
I already told you.
My darkness swallows everything around it.
Whether it's punches, blades, bullets, lightning, or fire.
Unlike you, I can't just turn into an element and dodge an attack.
And the pain I absorb when I get hit is much greater than what a normal human feels.
But the trade-off for that inconvenience is more than worth it.
Because there happens to be one other thing I can absorb.
Black Vortex!
First, I use the gravity of darkness to pull a devil-proof power holder into my grasp.
Oh!
Uh!
Too strong!
And then when I touch the-
Uh-uh!
Uh!
Ha!
It's been so long since you've been hit.
I bet you forgot how much it hurts, Ace.
But you understand now.
You understood the second I grabbed you.
Not only can my darkness pull you in, it can also absorb your devil fruit power.
In other words, as long as they're in contact with me, someone with devil fruit powers is
no different than a normal human.
Logia, Zoan, Parameathia, all those with devil fruit powers who have become dependent on them
are in for a surprise.
One little touch will remind them how weak they really are.
Then all I have to do is avoid you.
Black Vortex!
Say no mouse, fire!
Everything falls before darkness.
And you can only struggle for so long.
Still finishing you off here would be a waste of your talent.
Don't fight it, Ace.
Join me!
If I surrender to you, then I can never call myself a man again.
I won't submit and I won't live with regrets no matter what.
You got that, stupid?
Once you die, your morals are useless.
I'm sorry you can't understand that, Ace.
Darkness taken!
Great Flame Commandments!
Flame Emperor!
The sun against darkness, huh?
Only one can win!
I'll make Whitebeard the king.
Fear…
Or die trying.
Fear…!
Fire…!
You
Three hours before aces execution the warlords take their place at Navy headquarters waiting for white beard to make his move with the three admirals on the scene
Tensions flare before what is sure to be a desperate struggle for pirates and marines alike
On the next one piece special retrospective before Marineford three Navy Admirals come together